A. Mithursan (ACPM)

Lecturer (Temporary), Tutor Mentor (CDCE)
Department of Management Studies,
Faculty of Management [FOM], University of Peradeniya [UOP], Sri Lanka.
mithursan@mgt.pdn.ac.lk/mithursan@gmail.com
+94 778-520-481 (mobile)

Google Scholar: A. Mithursan - Google Scholar

Research Gate: <u>Mithursan Asokkumar (researchgate.net)</u> LinkedIn: <u>www.linkedin.com/in/mithursanasokkumar</u>

SSRN: Author ID: 6895294



S

 \mathbf{S}

PROFILE

Welcome to my profile! I am a lecturer in the Department of Management Studies at the <u>Faculty of Management</u>, <u>University of Peradeniya</u>. My research interests include healthcare management, entrepreneurship (neuroentrepreneurship, social entrepreneurship), Sustainability and, experimental research (behavioral and experimental economics, management experiments). I am also involved in projects related to the plural sector and NGOs. I actively contribute to research in these areas and have received recognition for my academic and research accolades. I am actively exploring opportunities to collaborate with ongoing projects.

EDUCATION



▶ BBA (Hons) in Organizational Management (2019 – 2023)

Faculty of Management, University of Peradeniya, Sri Lanka

- CGPA: 3.8/4.00 (2nd rank in the batch, among 162 students, batch-top in majoring module)
- Thesis: Experimenting the Role of Pro-sociality on the Effort and Engagement of Nursing Professionals in Sri Lanka (Best Paper Award 2023)
- ➤ Chartered Accountant of Sri Lanka Corporate Level (R) (2024)
- **▶** International Summer Program (2022)

Saitama University, Japan (ID. No: 22IZ222)

- Modules:
- Global Agenda and International Development in the Japanese Perspective
- Economic Strategies in Japan and Asia
- Animation Studies S
- Japanese Language Class for Absolute Beginners

 (The highest grade in Japan grading S, A.,)

➢ General Certificate of Education (Advanced) Level (2017)

Mu/Yogapuram National School, Sri Lanka

- Business Studies-A Economics-A Accounting- A
- Z-score- 1.6009 District 3rd Rank

MEMBERSHIPS & APPOINTMENTS



- Associate Member of The Institute of Chartered Professional Managers of Sri Lanka
 - Membership Number: ACPM02641
- > Tutor Mentor for BBA Online Degree Programme 2024, CDCE.
- ➤ iPURSE 2024, Editorial Board member, University of Peradeniya.
- Criterion 6: SER writing team member for BBA (Honours) Degree Programme, Faculty of Management 2024
- ➤ Volunteer Student Counsellor, Faculty of Management, University of Peradeniya (2023 to present)
- National Coordinating Secretary of United Nature International Peace Sri Lanka.
- ➤ Guest Lecturer, "Entrepreneurial Mindset "at the Future Fusion 2024
- Research and Internship Evaluation Panel member, Faculty of Management

ACADEMIC DISTINCTIONS/ AWARDS



- University Prize for Academic Excellence
- Faculty Award Winner, 2024
- Gold Medal for Best Researcher Award, 2023
- International Young Achiever Award 2024, at the Global Leadership Summit
- ➤ Batch Top in Major Module/ 2nd Rank in Batch
- ➤ Dean's list: Highest GPA Scorer in Multiple Semesters
- ➤ Gold Medal for Innovative Business Idea Competition, 2022 (Organized by the Business Linkage, Innovation, Incubation and Technology Transfer Office (BLII-TTO), University of Peradeniya)
- > Best Research Paper Award, Management Undergraduate Research Symposium, 2023
- ➤ Best Research Paper Award, 8th International Conference on Contemporary Management, 2024
- Extra-Mural Gold Medal Award Nominee, 2024
- ➤ Best Performer, Management Undergraduate Internship Symposium, 2023
- Represented the University of Peradeniya as a Team Leader at the European Union-funded INNOTAL Business Idea Competition among 30 teams from state universities in India, Sri Lanka, and Nepal; became the Finalist and secured 4th place.
- ➤ ICEN 2023 Conference Scholarship Holder.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES



Temporary Lecturer (15th September 2023-14th September 2024)

Department of Management Studies, Faculty of Management, University of Peradeniya

- Assists senior academic staff in carrying out their undergraduate teaching and research activities
- Conducted discussions, main lectures, and practical sessions for BBA Hons. and B. Com undergraduates
- Organize and facilitate workshops, industry collaboration, curriculum development, and contribute to the department and research development projects



Management Assistant/ Student Counselor

(30th May 2023-8th September 2023)

International Academic Office, National Institute of Business Management, Sri Lanka

- ➤ Worked with existing foreign Universities
- ➤ Mainly handled student's transfer programs
- > Developed partnerships with new foreign universities
- ➤ Attended professional development workshops & External prospective student's meet up



Research Assistant (5th August 2024-Now)

Faculty of Management, University of Peradeniya, Sri Lanka.

➤ "Working as a Research Assistant, supervising research enumerators across Agro-based cooperatives in the Northern, Central, Western, and Southern provinces under the study titled 'The Commercialization Process of Cooperatives: A Study on the Double Bottom Line Approach of Agricultural Cooperative Societies in Sri Lanka."



Research Assistant (5th December 2020-31st March 2024)

International Food Policy Research Institute

- ➤ Working for the project on "Influence of food environments on diet quality" under the R5n project conducted by the collaboration of the World Food Program, International Food Policy Research Institute, Johns Hopkins University, and the University of Peradeniya.
- ➤ The R5n project supports Sri Lanka's most vulnerable rural communities to enhance their resilience against recurrent natural shocks, reduce and mitigate climate risk through the reconstruction of productive assets, and ensure recovery and diversification of livelihoods.



Research Assistant (10th January 2022-20th April 2023)

Massey University, New Zealand

➤ Worked as a Research Assistant in MASSEY University, New Zealand Ph.D Research in the study of "A Model on Sustainable Farmer Development in Developing Countries: A Test on Dairy Value Chains".



Research Assistant (5th February 2022-30th August 2022)

Sarvodaya, Sri Lanka

➤ Engaged with the Sarvodaya community-based research work under the UNICEF-funded project during COVID-19 titled "Strengthening the knowledge, skills, and practices of communities and community leaders on COVID-19 related prevention and response measures". The main objective of the study is to increase public awareness of protective and proactive measures to keep the public safe during the COVID-19.



Management Intern (13th September 2022-12th December 2022)

Central Bank of Sri Lanka

Functioned as an Intern at the Central Bank of Sri Lanka, for their 3-month intensive internship programme. Functioned under 6 departments namely; Internal Audit Department, Policy review and Monitoring Department, EPF Employee Provident Fund Department, Finance Department, Economic Research Department and, Bank Supervision Department.

Performed tasks and duties assigned by supervisors, pertaining to each division within the departments, to learn and understand the systems and processes conducted by the Central Bank of Sri Lanka. Assignments ranged between Research, Analysis, and Investment valuation using published and internal data. Had the Opportunity to work with bank professionals ranging from director level to the bottom line. At the end of the Internship, gained knowledgeabout the entire processes conducted within each of the assigned departments.



United Nature International Peace, Sri Lanka

As a national coordinating secretary, I was responsible to form the national executive committee and several teams all over the districts to work under number of projects. During the Covid-19 pandemic situation, I took the leadership and successfully completed number of societal and health development projects.



Bank of Ceylon

As a national coordinating secretary, I was responsible to form the national executive committee and several teams all over the districts to work under number of projects. During the Covid-19 pandemic situation, I took the leadership and successfully completed number of societal and health development projects.

RESEARCH PUBLICATIONS



- Samaranayake, D.I.J., Jayarthna, H.G.D., Mithursan, A. (2024). "Impact of Identity Fusion and Pro-group Motivation on Employees' Productivity: Experimental Survey". *Munich Personal RePEc Archive (MPRA)*. pp.120948. https://mpra.ub.uni-muenchen.de/120948/.
- Mithursan, A., Fernando, N.T.K.P., Samaranayake, D.I.J., Maheswaran, S. (2024). Towards a Paradigm Shift with Neuro-Entrepreneurship Education: A Lesson for the Developing Asian Nations. *KDU Journal of Multidisciplinary Studies* 2024. Vol.6(1). pp.81-94. DOI: https://doi.org/10.4038/kjms.v6i1.112. ORCID iD: 0009-0009-2423-4729.
- Samaranayake, D.I.J., Maheswaran, S., Mithursan, A. (2024). Social Enterprise Intention of Non-STEM University Students: Experimental Evidence. *Journal of Business Research and Insights*. Vol.10(1).
- Saheer, M.N.M., Mithursan, A., Samaranayake, D.I.J. (2024). The Impact of Government Intervention in Mitigating the Shadow Economy: Special Reference to Colombo District in Sri Lanka Special Reference to Colombo District, Sri Lanka. Available at SSRN: <a href="https://ssrn.com/abstract="htt
- Ransha, R.R.P.H., Mithursan, A., Samaranayake, D.I.J. (2024). Exploring the Interplay Between Organizational Mission Drift, Motivation and Commitment of Emerging Social Workers. Sri Lanka Journal of Management Studies (SLJMS). ORCID iD: 0009-0009-2423-4729.
- Mithursan, A., Samaranayake, D.I.J. (2024). "Role of Prosocial Motivation in Improving Service Performance and Equity of Care Provided by Nursing professionals in Sri Lanka", *Journal of Public Health Research*, 2024. (*Journal proceeding*).
- Mithursan, A., Samaranayake, D.I.J., Maheswaran, S. (2024). Social as an Epiphenomenon of Economics! Experimenting Young People's Social Enterprise Intention in a Developing Country. 8th International Conference on Contemporary Management 2024. International Conference on Contemporary Management | University of Jaffna (jfn.ac.lk).

- Mithursan, A., Fernando, N.T.K.P., Samaranayake, D.I.J., Maheswaran, S. (2024). A Systematic Review on the Paradigm shift in Neuroentrepreneurship Education across Developing Asian Countries: Visualization and Analysis. *Sri Lanka Forum of Entrepreneurship-2024*. <u>SLFE (kln.ac.lk)</u>. (Full Paper).
- Mithursan, A., Fernando, N.T.K.P. (2024) A PRISMA Review on the Paradigm Shift in Neuroentrepreneurship Education across Asian Developing Countries: Visualization and Analysis. Faculty Working Paper Series, February-2024, Faculty of Management, University of Peradeniya. (Extended Abstract).
- ➤ Ransha, R.R.P.H., Mithursan, A., Samaranayake, D.I.J. (2024). Exploring the Interplay Between Organizational Mission Drift, Motivation and Commitment of Emerging Social Workers. *The Fifth Research Conference on Business Studies* 2024 (RCBS). University of Vavuniya, Sri Lanka. (Full Paper).
- Rila, R., Mithursan, A., Samaranayake. D.I.J. (2024). The Effectiveness of Green-Nudges in promoting Water Conservation and Fostering Sustainability Mindset in an Educational Setting. *International Conference on Social Sciences and Languages*. Sabaragamuwa University of Sri Lanka.
- Mithursan, A., Samaranayake, D.I.J. (2023). "Experimenting the role of Pro-sociality on the Effort and Engagement of Nursing professionals in Sri Lanka", 9th Peradeniya International Economic Research (PIERS) Conference, 2023. http://dx.doi.org/10.13140/RG.2.2.12176.58880. (Extended Abstract).
- Anushiya, K., Mithursan, A., Zhang, H. (2023). Impact of covid-19 on the marketing strategies of small and medium enterprises in Jaffna district. *Sri Lankan Japan Collaborative Research*. Issue. 8. ISSN:3051-5777. https://site.pdn.ac.lk/centers/sljsc/con23.html.
- ➤ Hathy, A., Mithursan, A., Samaranayake, D.I.J. (2023). Efficacy of Green Nudges on Resource and Energy Conservation-A Systematic Review. *The International Conference on Eco Health Nexus: Bridging Cascade Ecology and Human Well-Being*.
- ➤ Mithursan, A., Ransa, R.R.P.H., Samaranayake, D.I.J. (2023). Experimenting the Impact of Organizational Mission Drift on Motivation and Effort of Nascent Social Workers in Sri Lanka. 20th International Conference on Business Management (ICBM).
- Mithursan, A., Samaranayake, D.I.J. (2023). "Experimenting the role of Pro-sociality on the Effort and Engagement of Nursing professionals in Sri Lanka", Management Undergraduate Research symposium 2023.
- Mithursan, A., Samaranayake, D.I.J. (2024). Impact of Patriotism on Motives of Covid-19 Prevention: Experimental Evidence proceeding on Sri Lankan Journal of Management Studies. (Journal proceeding).
- > Yomal.R.A.P.G, Mithursan.A, Samaranayake.D.I.J, (2024). The Effect of Contextual Tax Framing on Compliance Rate for Income Tax among SMEs in Kandy District. *Journal of Business and Technology*. https://jbt.sljol.info. (Journal proceeding).

MAGAZINE PUBLICATIONS



- ➤ Mithursan, A. (2024) Empowering Futures: Sri Lankan Undergraduates and the Entrepreneurial Frontier. Vol.1. issue-01. *Management Reader*, Faculty of Management, University of Peradeniya.
- ➤ Mithursan, A. (2023) Exploring the role of Entrepreneurship and Resource Utilization in Empowering Sri Lankan Undergraduates within an Innovative Economy. Vol.4. *Management Reader*, Faculty of Management, University of Peradeniya.
- ➤ Mithursan, A. (2022) "It takes two to tango" Can the monetary policy of the central bank of Sri Lanka alone control inflation? Vol.3. *Management Reader*, Faculty of Management, University of Peradeniya.

- Mithursan, A. (2022). The Success story of women entrepreneur. *Agriculture Faculty of English Literary Association AFELA Outlook*. University of Peradeniya.
- Mithursan, A. (2022). A Throwback to better time at university. *Peradeniya Management Student Magazine*. Faculty of Management, University of Peradeniya.

LEADERSHIPS AND PANNELS SERVED



- ➤ Internship Evaluation Panel Coordinator, Department of Management Studies, Faculty of Management, University of Peradeniya.
- Research Evaluation Pannel Coordinator, Department of Management Studies, Faculty of Management, University of Peradeniya.
- ➤ The President of the Organization Management Students' Society, University of Peradeniya (2021-2022).
- ➤ Project head, Zero Plastic National Movement Webinar series (2022).
- > Overall Project Coordinator of We Lead Society, University of Peradeniya (2022-2023).
- Active Member of Rotaract Club, University of Peradeniya.
- Active Member of the Career Guidance Unit, University of Peradeniya.
- Management Faculty Coordinator of Peradeniya University Karate Games 2021.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS AND DEVELOPMENT



- > Completed a Professional Development Program organized by Deakin University, Australia (one week).
- > Delegate at the Local Conference of Youth Sri Lanka (three-day workshop).
- ➤ Delegate at the International Model United Nations Conference, 2021
- Analytical Skills: Research, Case study development
- ➤ Business Skills: Business Model Development, Strategic Management
- Sustainability skills: Sustainable Leadership, Knowledge and Implementation of Sustainable Practices
- Mentoring and Leadership Skills: Guest/ Mentor at the Future Fusion organized by Plantation Ministry, in collaboration with AISEC, SLIIT Kandy and University of Peradeniya
- Language Skills: Tamil (Native), English (Fluent), Sinhala (Fluent), Japanese (Absolute Beginner)

CERTIFICATIONS AND TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES:



- Practical knowledge of statistical packages STATA, R Studio, Minitab, and SPSS
- Practical knowledge of Accounting Software: Quick Book, MYOB, Sage Business Cloud Computing, E-tally, and Excel
- ➤ Hands on experience in Microsoft Office packages: Microsoft Word, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Power Point, Microsoft Access
- > Delegate (50/Asia-Pacific Region) Japan International Youth Innovation Summit, 2024
- ➤ Certified in Sage Business Cloud Accounting Software (scored 94/100 in course evaluation)
- > Successfully Completed Course on Career Development, Career Guidance Unit, University of Peradeniya
- Certified in Lean Six Sigma White Belt
- > Outstanding achievement as a finalist in the INNOTAL Student Business Idea Competition
- > Certificate for Excellence Performance in the INNOTAL Business Idea Competition
- Successfully Completed the Japan Modernization Course (JICA) in 2021
- ➤ Diploma in English (Intermediate Level) British Council AJF001515

- > Diploma in English, Microsoft office (Excel, PowerPoint, and other applications), Hardware and, Accounting package (E-tally) from DMI Education
- Second Language: Sinhala Language Exam-"B" pass.
- ➤ 3rd Runner-up in Provincial Level Carrom Competition
- > Successfully completed the Youth Basketball Coaching Camp.
- > Certificate for the completion of Preventing Violent Extremism through Youth Online Engagement Course.

REFERENCES



Mr. D.I.J. Samaranayake Senior Lecturer/ Research Supervisor, Department of Management Studies, Faculty of Management, University of Peradeniya +44 7861 743532

Email: dijs@mgt.pdn.ac.lk

Dr. S. Maheswaran, Head of the Department/ Co-Author, Department of Operations Management, Faculty of Management, University of Peradeniya +94 77 784 2232

Email: mahessiva@mgt.pdn.ac.lk

DECLARATION

I, the undersigned, certify that to the best of my knowledge and belief, resume correctly describe me, my qualification and my experience. I understand that any will fall misstatement described herein may lead to my disqualification

Mithursan Asokkumar 25th September 2024